Eloise Hubbard Linscott collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series III: Graphic Materials, 200 black-and-white photos, 30 film negatives
  - Subseries C: Itemized list of photographs
    - The "Shenandoah" (sailing vessel), undated, 1 photo print: black and white; 4 x 4.75 in.; afc1942002_ph240
Metosanya, also referred to as “Princess Metosanya,” was a performer from Beverly, Massachusetts. Linscott's notes also refer to her as “Mrs. Karl Holt” (Mildred S. Holt). Because Linscott refers to her most often as “Metosanya,” this is the name used in the collection, with “Princess Metosanya” used as an alternate name.
In Linscott's notes, Needahbeh is sometimes called “Chief” Needahbeh. The name “Needahbeh” appears in two variations in the collection materials (in Linscott’s handwriting): “Needahbeh” and “Nee dah beh.” Online searches and examples in the Linscott correspondence (from Needahben) led to the final decision on the most appropriate presentation of the name.
Dick Richardson, a noted fiddler whose work has been collected by others, is usually named "Burt" in Linscott’s notes. However, his name appears in the Library of Congress Name Authority File (LCNAF) as "Dick Richardson," and he released a cassette entitled, "Dick Richardson: Old Time New Hampshire Fiddler."
Name and variations
Will E. Ayer Will Ayer Will Avery
Lillian Beacham Lillian Beecham
Georgia Mae Georgia May
John Hutchinson Johnny Hutchinson John Hudson
Isaac McNeilly James McNeilly
Metosanya; Princess Metosanya Mrs. Karl Holt
Needahbeh; Chief Needabeh Nee dah beh Needahben; Nee bah ben
Potter, Charles W. (Charlie) Porter, Charles W. (Charlie)
Potter, Ellis Porter, Ellis
Dick Richardson Burt Richardson
Abraham (Abe) Washburn Al Washburn; also Washburne
Other transcription or editing errors
Folk Songs of Old New England contains the names of certain people whose performances Linscott recorded, and with whom she corresponded, but whose names were misspelled in publication (and may have been subsequently handwritten incorrectly by Linscott). It is possible that these spelling errors were editorial oversights, but it is also likely that Linscott misspelled them when writing the names down, and did not discover the errors. In the case of Frances Horn, Linscott names her as “Frances Merrow Horn” in the book; after the book’s publication, Frances Horn wrote to Linscott and explained that this was not her middle name, although it was a family name. (correspondence from Frances Horn to Linscott, January 16, 1940).
Bill Garity Bill Garrity; Wm. Garrity
Frances Horn Frances Merrow Horn
Denis Maclure Dennis McClure
Nicknames
Apart from transcription and abbreviation errors, there are also nicknames for certain people that appear in collection materials, with variations in frequency. The name used in this finding aid reflects the most common known usage, with nicknames or given names in parentheses.
George (Rocky Mountain George) Brown – nicknamed “Rocky Mountain” George Brown, the form of his name and nickname has been normalized in documentation for the collection.
Lena Bourne Fish – referred to as Granny Fish, sometimes as Grammie Fish (with the “ie” and the “y” as interchangeable endings). Since there is no definitive spelling, it has been excluded from the standardized form of the name in the collection.
Carrie B. Grover – her name appears thus in the Library of Congress Name Authority File. However, she signed many letters to Linscott as “Aunt Carrie.”
George Andrew (Stonewall) Jackson – The nickname appears infrequently, but seemed an informative addition for this noted New Hampshire legislator.
William J. (Jack) Sherrard – referred to as “Jack,” “W.J.,” and “WJS” in various collection materials. Sherrard also signed his name (in a unique instance) as “W.J. Beresford Sherrard.” (correspondence to Linscott, August 9, 1951).
Appendix B: Performers recorded by Linscott
This list includes (with some exceptions, such as Dick Richardson) non-commercial performers documented in the collection, with notes concerning relationships between performers, and with the collector, and other information, if known.
Adams, William A.
Ainsworth, Doreen caller for the Texas Ramblers
Ambrose, Langdon
Andrews, Eugene (Gene)
Anne Anne Linscott?
Appleby, Laura wife of Milton Appleby
Appleby, Milton husband of Laura Appleby
Arno, Elmer
Ayer, Will E.
Bailey, Alec
Beale, Andrew
Beacham, Lillian
Bent, Manson R.
Best, Dick
Bourne Male Quartet and Chorus
Brock, L.C. (Pop)
Brown, Alvin son of Asa Brown
Brown, Asa father of Alvin Brown
Brown, George (Rocky Mountain George)
Carr, Clarice
Carroll, Jimmy
Cassidy, Clare
Cates, Frank
Cheney, Lillian M.
Cole, Edson H.
Comstock, Lois A.
Converse, Harvey (Doc) leader, New Hampshire Guides Orchestra
Cotton Mountain Boys
Crosby, Alice Ballard (Mrs. William O. Crosby)
Cushman, Roy, Mrs.
Cyr, Alice
Davey, Everett
Day, Ed
Deane, Agnes E., Miss
Delude’s Dance Orchestra
Dennis, Harry
Edgerly, Gil
Edwards, Joseph (Buddy)
Farnham, Herbert D. (Bert) husband of H. Rae Farnham; father of Betty Gaye Farnham
Farnham, H. Rae (Mrs. Herbert D.) wife of Herbert D. Farnham; mother of Betty Gaye Farnham
Farnham, Betty Gaye daughter of Herbert D. and H. Rae Farnham
Finnemore, Eileen (Mrs. Clifford)
Fish, Lena Bourne
Ford, Ada
Fortune, Stewart
French, Nathan music transcription only
Frye, Serena J.
Frye, Mary P.
Fuller, Ethel K.
Garrity, William (Bill)
Gene Head, Gene
GHR Reed, George?
Glidden, Lyle
Grover, Carrie B. (Mrs. Almon R. Grover)
Hale, Happy
Hanson, Arthur W.
Hardy, Val
Head, Gene
Helen Helen Hubbard Bonner? (Helen Hubbard Bonner was the younger sister of Eloise Hubbard Linscott)
High School Quartette [sic]
Hillis, Eric
Hitchcock, Jim
Hodgkins, Bert
Horn, Frances
Howe, Ina, Mrs.
Hubbard, Ann
Hunter, Mable Johnson
Hutchinson, John
Jackson, George Andrew (Stonewall)
Jenney, Charles
Katahdin Mountaineers
King, Walter
Laconte, Lizzie
Larkin, Edwin L.
Larrabee, Harold
Lewis, Edward A.
Linscott, Charles Hardy husband of the collector, father of John Hubbard Linscott
Linscott, Charles "Bonnie Prince Charley"; grandson of the collector; son of John Hubbard Linscott
Linscott, Anne related to Charles Hardy Linscott
Linscott, Eloise Hubbard
Linscott, John Hubbard son of the collector
Luther, Sid
MacIver, Beaulieu A.
Mann, David
McClure, Dennis
McNeilly, Isaac
Meatty, Herbert
Meatty, Maynard
Merrill, Ralph
Metosanya also known as Princess Metosanya; Mrs. Karl Holt
Miller, Al
Minot, Abbie
Moody
Morning Star
Needabeh Chief Needabeh (Roland Eugene Nelson)
Neptune, Joseph, Father
Neptune, William
New Hampshire Guides Band SEE Converse, Harvey (Doc)
Page, Ralph
Paine, Smith
Parris, Leroy (Roy)
Partridge, Bob
Peirce, David, Captain
Porter, Charles W. (Charlie)
Porter, Ellis [?]
Powers, Llewellyn S.
Prindle, Royall
Pritchard, Margaret M., Mrs.
Pullen, Fred
Quigley, Albert (Al)
Radford, Cassius (Cash) also known as Cassius Marcus Radford
Reed, George
Remick, Pauline (Polly)
Reynolds, Maynard
Richards, Albert S.
Richardson, Dick also known as Halton J. Richardson
Ring, Louise
Roberts, Frank, Mrs.
Robie, Alice
Robie, Eldridge
Robinson, Roger father of Roland Robinson
Robinson, Robbie
Robinson, Roland son of Roger Robinson
Ronco, Charles (Uncle Charlie)
Sargent, Chet
Shaker Singers, The
Sherman, Elna
Sherrard, William J. (Jack)
Simpson, Harry A.
Simpson, Harry A., Mrs.
Simpson, Mary
Simpson, Peter
Singing Smiths, The SEE Smith, R.V. (Raymond Ven)
Smith, Charlton Lyman, Captain
Smith, R.V. (Raymond Ven) performed with The Singing Smiths
Smith, Wynifred Staples, Mrs. daughter of Gene Staples
Spink, William (Bill)
Staples, Gene father of Wynifred Staples Smith
Stead, Charles
Stead, Harold
Stead, Harold, Mrs.
Swett, David M. (Dave)
Texas Ramblers SEE Ainsworth, Doreen; White, Dave
Tomah, Sebat
Tomah, Sammy
Virgin, Hiram
Walden, Arthur Treadwell
Washburn, Abraham (Abe)
Webber, Belle, Mrs.
Welch, Harry
White, Dave (with the Texas Ramblers)
Williams, Grace, Mrs.
Woodward, Willie (Bill)
Young, Sam, Jr.
Young, Sam, Sr.
Young, Nathansel (Ansel)
Appendix C: Geographic names
These locations are listed as documented in the collection. When noting locations, Linscott did not always differentiate between the city and state associated with the performer, and the location where the recording was made.
Connecticut
Farmington
Mystic
Willimantic
Maine
Berry’s Mills
Bowdoinham
Carthage
Dixfield
Dover-Foxcroft
East Limington
East Parsonfield
Edgecomb
Friendship
Gorham
Hiram
Limerick
Mexico
North Anson
Norway
Old Town
Peter Dana Point
Phippsburg
Pleasant Point
Portland
Raymond
Rockland
Sebago Lake
Swanville
West Scarborough
Massachusetts
Beverly
Boston
Brookline
Cambridge
Dedham
Fitchburg
Foster's Pond
Framingham
Gloucester
Hancock Shaker Village
Jamaica Plain
Lenox
Marblehead
Marlborough
Medfield
Needham
New Bedford
Newton
North Wilmington
Pittsfield
Springfield
Taunton
New Hampshire
Berlin
Bristol
Brookfield
Camp Ossipee
Canterbury
Clarsville
Colebrook
Concord
Dummer
Durham
East Barrington
East Jaffrey
East Jaffrey
Enfield
Errol
Freedom
Gonic
Hillsborough
Hinsdale
Kidderville
Laconia
Lancaster
Lebanon
Lincoln
Manchester
Melvin Village
Munsonville
Nelson
Ossipee
Pittsburg
Pleasant Valley
Pontocook Dam
Portsmouth
Shelburne
Stark
Tamworth
Wolfeboro
New Mexico
Cochiti
Rhode Island
Chepachet
North Kingstown
Wickford
Vermont
Chelsea
Saint Johnsbury
Washington, D.C.
Appendix D: Elizabeth Foster Reed’s copy book: Concordance for titles and digital ID numbers
Titles in the concordance for the copy book (i.e., the music manuscript notebook) reflect the spelling, capitalization, and punctuation of the titles as they appear in the book itself. The ID number for each digital scan appears to the right of the title, with some titles appearing on more than one page, and in one instance not on consecutive pages. Descriptive information appears in brackets for untitled works.
Adams Favourite afc1942002_ms071_0020
American March afc1942002_ms071_0003
Away with Melancholy afc1942002_ms071_0004
The Beggar Girl afc1942002_ms071_0007
The Bewildered Maid afc1942002_ms071_0035, 0036
Bonapartes March afc1942002_ms071_0019
Bonapartes March Crossing the Rhine afc1942002_ms071_0029
Bride’s Farewell afc1942002_ms071_0014, 0015, 0016
Bruce’s March afc1942002_ms071_0025
Buy a broom afc1942002_ms071_0024
The Cheat afc1942002_ms071_0031
Come To The Sunset-Tree afc1942002_ms071_0005
Copenhagen Waltz afc1942002_ms071_0030
A favorite Reel. in imitation of Bagpipe afc1942002_ms071_0009
Flemmings March afc1942002_ms071_0027, 0028
Has sorrow thy young days shared afc1942002_ms071_0008, 0009
Home Sweet Home. A Quick Step afc1942002_ms071_0018
Honey Moon afc1942002_ms071_0003
Hours there were afc1942002_ms071_0010, 0011
Hulls [sic] Victory afc1942002_ms071_0017
Hungarian Air with variations afc1942002_ms071_0033, 0034
Java March afc1942002_ms071_0006
Jefferson March afc1942002_ms071_0004
Kathleen O Moore afc1942002_ms071_0005
Kitty Clover, No 1 afc1942002_ms071_0040
Land of sweet Erin afc1942002_ms071_0007
The Lavender Girl afc1942002_ms071_0012, 0013
Louisville March afc1942002_ms071_0028
Massachusetts March afc1942002_ms071_0029
O dear what can the matter be afc1942002_ms071_0006
Oh no we never mention her afc1942002_ms071_0015
Panharmonican [sic] March afc1942002_ms071_0030
Quadrille afc1942002_ms071_0031
The Rout afc1942002_ms071_0025
The Soldier’s Joy afc1942002_ms071_0032
Steam boat Quick step afc1942002_ms071_0011
Swiss Guards March afc1942002_ms071_0017
Swiss Waltz afc1942002_ms071_0018
Waltz afc1942002_ms071_0036
The Washing Day afc1942002_ms071_0026, 0027